what's up guys I'm coach pregnant
resident this video is going to teach
you how to maximize your squat ever so
the first thing I want to talk to you
about is your torso lead now even hip
joint angle the more upright you are the
deeper you're going to be so see here
you got a big forward lean I'm not
changing the hip angle but the warm-up
right I am
see how I end up going below parallel
you don't change the hip angle you just
change whether the femur gets below
parallel or not just by changing the
angle of the torso so if you have
trouble hitting squat depth it's your
best interest to be upright everyone has
unique skeletal Anatomy of their hips
and their ankles so some people have
good angle towards the plectrum a really
good hip mobility other people not so
much
and there's only so much you can do to
improve it
so the first thing we want to do is
increase our hip flexion mobility in
order to squat deep you got to sink the
hips deep there are a lot of good hip
mobility drills and I encourage you to
type in hip flexor mobility drills onto
YouTube you'll get a lot of different
ideas here are some of them
you
next step we want to also improve our
ink
mobility to squat deep your knees won't
travel out far because you're going to
be upright you know what ankle
dorsiflexion range of motion so there
are a lot of different drills you can do
here as well
you
in a squat variation that has the logo
on the front is going to help you get
deeper just because it helps you
maintain a more upright torso position
so instead of doing back squats
if you perform front squats and you can
do this clean grip or across her rib
you're going to stay more upright here
therefore you get deeper drop the squat
you can spin where up right here so
godless what's in front spots are very
good ultras if you're trying to get
deeper as well
most people around 10% stronger using
the lower back squat position compared
to high water the high bar position does
help you stay more upright and therefore
helps you go deeper and here's the
reason why when you do low bar C you're
going to lean a little bit more so say
this is as deep as my hips will go I'm
bigger than a parallel if I go I bought
and I end up staying more upright now I
didn't take my hip angle but I've got a
couple inches deeper so choose high bar
over low bar
elevating your heels is a good strategy
to get deeper the spot because
eliminating the hills starts you off in
a little bit of plantar flexion and
therefore when you go deep you're not
using all of your ankle dorsiflexion
range of motion more upright it better
squat down so squat shoes are a good
alternative a have elevated heels on
them okay that's one option also you can
use a wedge like a yoga wedge or just
elevate your heels out of five or ten
out of plates this is an immediate
solution for a lot of people it's one
thing elevate their heels almost certain
you can space so much more upright see
that and therefore you can get really
deep even though if I hip angle is not
so severe see that I'm very upright a
very deep up level of parallel but I
don't have a crazy good thing
so everyone has a unique setup that
maximizes their spot depth you can
generally want to toy around with your
stance with your level up foot flare and
also help for you push your knees out
when your level will get that don't you
some people swap deepest with a narrow
stance with feet pointed straight ahead
so people will have wide stance
something wide stance flared out
everywhere between you needed twice
round with all the different variations
in order to feel what does give you the
deepest depth you can also give it a
pocket pet position like this and go
narrower sit back put a little bit wider
back try to count up these out more seek
that but in general you can also learn
that from a standing position for
example if I go wide like this this is
as deep as I can get right here just
barely below parallel but if I go medium
stance feet flare still went deeper I
can get if I keep my feet straight I
cannot get nearly as deep so take the
time to figure out your optimal stance
with fuller and get the abduction
how conclude activation help improve
your squad le
well when the glutes contract it
actually inserts a rearward pull on the
heads of femur so it pulls rearward in
the acetabulum and then you don't have
the contact up here in the front so that
may help you get a little bit deeper in
the squat there are plenty of loss of
glute activation drills you can
experiment to figure out your favorite
ones
you
now anytime you're more upright you're
gonna feel the quad or get a little
harder so just flood upright you need
strong quad well what things can you
straight to the quads of course front
squats high bar squats got this one but
also things like leg extension leg press
Bulgarian split squat all of these
things can help transfer to the squat so
those were eight different tips to help
you improve your squat down some of
those will work for you others won't I
encourage you to experiment with all of
them and then determine which one's work
best for you last I want to touch on why
you want to improve your squat there
it's mainly for powerlifting in power
looking you have to descend below
parallel so the hip crease has to
descend below the knee joint and so if
you're a power lifter and it's really
tough to get down then these strategies
are gonna be great for you what if
you're just training for physique /
aesthetics well that case I implore you
to not be so obsessed with squat depth
and here's why number one
squatting deep can be problematic for
some people some people get increased
pressure on the knees when they go deep
and some people get increased stress on
the low back especially people who
bubbling around on a lower back
successively
so if you're in that category don't
obsess about getting jabbed or getting
in rock bottom as well it is true that a
large range of motion is superior for
muscle hypertrophy
however it's not going to make the
biggest difference with you squat just
above parallel or just below parallel he
built a fine physique squatting a little
bit above
or just two parallel and never going
rock bottom whereas the grass and this
is true with the quadriceps it's true of
the glutes you need to figure out your
ideal stance and set up along with your
optimal variations that allow you to
squat week in and week out pain and
injury free of coach record dress thank
you for watching